Hello English learners, welcome back
to another lesson with us at English
Pod, my name is Marko and I'm
Erica and today we don't feel very good.
That's right, actually in this lesson
we're talking about a hangover.
Hangover, wow, that's an
interesting word, what does that mean?
Well, when you drink beer or wine
or vodka, you drink too much a bit.
The next morning you have a hangover.
Okay, so a lot of our listeners have
probably experienced a hangover before.
It's very likely, but the problem is when
you have to go to work the next day.
Yes, and you might need to
actually miss work, but you need
some good words and phrases
to describe how bad you feel.
Okay, so let's listen to this
dialogue for the first time.
We have a guy describing his hangover
and why he missed work that day.
Are you okay, man? You don't
look very well. You feel terrible.
I went out last night with Trevor
and things got a little out of hand.
Nice, so where did you guys go?
Well, we hit up a couple of local
bars and met up with some friends.
Everything was cool until
Mike came along and it
turned out that it was
his birthday yesterday.
Oh no, Mike's birthday
is a drink fest for sure.
And tell me about it. We
drink everything in the bar.
Is that why he
missed work today?
Yeah, I woke up this morning
feeling really nauseous.
I threw up like five times.
Ew!
I was so dehydrated
that I drank a gallon of
water and my head has
been pounding all day.
I swear, I am never going to drink again.
Too bad, man. Tonight
is Tracy's going away
party and she asked if
you were going to go.
Oh yeah, I'm there.
All right, so he's never
drinking again, but then at
the next chance for a party,
he's already ready to go.
I think that's the typical lie
of every person that drinks.
They'll never drink again, but a week
later or a month later, they are again.
Or a day later.
All right, so we saw
some great vocab here,
so let's look at it now
in language takeaway.
I'm going to look at five words here.
Now the first one, they talked about
how Mike's birthday is a drink fest.
A drink fest.
It's a drink fest.
All right, so we have this word drink fest.
Now what is this fest part?
Well, maybe you recognize
the word october fest.
Okay, or festival. So fest is like a party.
There's lots of food,
there's lots of drink.
A drink fest is an event
where there's a lot of drinks.
Okay, so can I have
different types of fest?
Yeah, this is a really
informal sort of slang
way of saying there's
lots of something.
So I could say, oh my
god, it's a puppy fest.
So there are a lot of puppies.
Or I can say like a fast food fest.
Okay, so we're eating a lot of fast food.
There's a lot of festival.
All right, so fast, interesting.
Now when he was describing his hangover,
he said that he felt really nauseous.
Nauscious.
Now I always have a hard
time spelling this word.
So N-A-U-S-E-O-U-S.
Nauscious.
It kind of seems like
you should say now seals.
Right, but you say nauseous.
Yeah, okay.
So when you're feeling
nauseous, what do you feel like?
So you feel dizzy, you
don't feel very well.
Like your stomach hurts.
Yeah, and your head is kind of spinning.
Okay, and you feel like you might throw up.
Right, exactly.
Now this word that you just mentioned,
throw up, is actually our next word.
And well, we're not going to describe it.
Why don't we just listen
to a person throwing up?
Oh, Marco, that was horrible.
Well, that's the only way we
could actually explain, throw up.
I mean, it's kind of a
hard word to explain,
but I'm sure everyone understands
now what it means, right?
Okay, the word is to throw up.
To throw up.
Our next word.
Now our guy who's hungover,
he said, "I was so dehydrated.
" Dehydrated.
To be dehydrated.
So this is an adjective, and it means
that I have no water in my body.
Exactly.
Okay, so I am dehydrated.
I need water.
Yeah, common feeling after
drinking too much beer, huh?
Exactly.
Now our final word, he
said he had a headache,
and he said, "My head's
been pounding all day.
" Okay, so his head has
Now this verb, "pounding."
It sounds like this.
All right, so a clear
example of what your head
feels like when you have
this very bad headache.
You can also say, "I have
a pounding headache."
I have a pounding headache, exactly.
Where my head is pounding.
All right, so five great words
that we just looked at right now.
So why don't we listen
to our dialogue a second
time, and let's slow
it down just a little bit,
and then we'll come back and
take a look at some phrases.
Are you okay, man?
You don't look very well.
You feel terrible.
I went out last night with Trevor,
and things got a little out of hand.
Nice.
So where did you guys go?
Well, we hit up a couple of local
bars and met up with some friends.
Everything was cool until Mike came along,
and it turned out that it
was his birthday yesterday.
Oh, no.
Mike's birthday is a drink fest for sure.
And tell me about it.
We drink everything in the bar.
Is that why you missed work today?
Yeah, I woke up this morning
feeling really nauseous.
I threw up like five times.
Ew.
I was so dehydrated
that I drank a gallon of
water, and my head has
been pounding all day.
I swear, I am never going to drink again.
Too bad, man.
Tonight is Tracy's going away party,
and she asked if you were going to go.
Oh, yeah, I'm there.
All right, well, that was a little
easier to understand this time.
Now you mentioned
that we've got some great
phrases, so let's go to
them now in Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
All right, so as we heard in the dialogue,
the party was, I think it
was a great party, right?
Well, it sounds like it was fantastic.
Well, apparently it was a great party,
and he said that he went out with Trevor,
and things got a little out of hand.
Things got a little out of hand.
Right, so things got a little out of hand.
Now, to get out of hand,
what does that mean?
Well, we have some examples,
so let's listen to a couple
of them before we explain it.
Example one.
Honey, the kids are
getting a little out of hand.
Can you do something?
Example two.
Guys, this argument is getting out of hand.
Let's all calm down.
Example three.
The party last night got out of hand.
The neighbor's called the police.
Okay, so when things get
out of hand, you lose control.
Exactly, they get out of
control just a little bit, maybe.
Yeah, go a little crazy.
All right, so things
got a little out of hand.
Now, the opposite of this
was everything was cool.
Everything was cool,
so everything was cool.
So basically everything was okay, everything
was relaxed, everything was going fine.
Exactly, and then Mike came along
and then things got a little out of hand.
Oh, that Mike.
And now for our last phrase,
he was describing that Mike's
birthday party was a drink fest, right?
And then his friend agreed.
He said, tell me about it.
Tell me about it.
Now, what does this mean?
Exactly, when he says, tell me about it.
Basically, it means I
completely understand.
I completely agree with you.
Yeah, okay.
So I could say, oh my god,
Marco, it's so hot outside today.
Right, and I would say, oh, I know.
Tell me about it.
Mm-hmm.
So I'm saying, yeah, I agree with you.
You are right.
Yeah.
Very good.
So these phrases, okay, so three
great phrases that we just looked at.
Let's listen to our
dialogue for the last time,
and then we'll come back
and talk a little bit more.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Are you okay, man?
You don't look very well.
Oh, you feel terrible.
I went out last night with Trevor,
and things got a little out of hand.
Nice.
So where did you guys go?
Well, we hit up a couple of local
bars and met up with some friends.
Everything was cool until Mike came along,
and it turned out that it
was his birthday yesterday.
Oh, no.
Mike's birthday is a drink fest for sure.
And tell me about it.
We drink everything in the bar.
Is that why he missed work today?
Yeah, I woke up this morning
feeling really nauseous.
I threw up like five times.
Ew.
I was so dehydrated
that I drank a gallon of
water, and my head has
been pounding all day.
I swear.
I am never going to drink again.
Too bad, man.
Tonight is Tracy's going away party.
And she asked if you were going to go.
Oh, yeah?
I'm there.
So it sounds like these guys sure like to
go out and have a few drinks, don't they?
Yeah, exactly.
And I think this is a very
common thing among
young people, usually
in the United States.
After a day at the office
or something they'll go,
or even Europe, they'll
go to the pub, right?
Yeah.
But the thing is that in America and Canada
we're very careful about
alcohol and young people, right?
Yeah, exactly.
The legal drinking age in
the most part of the United
States is 21 years of age,
and really many parents
or families will never let their
children drink alcohol until they're 21.
Right.
And also the laws that control
alcohol, like for example, on television,
if you notice a TV
commercial with beer or a wine,
you will never see the
person actually drinking it.
It's illegal.
Yeah, that's true.
While in other countries it's okay.
You'll see people
drinking it and having fun.
And these commercials
that can only maybe put
them close to their
lips but not drink it.
Interesting.
Another weird thing is that
sometimes you might want to sit
in your back garden or out on your
porch and have a beer after work, right?
But in places it's
totally illegal to do that.
You can't be outside with alcohol.
Right, you can't be seen drinking
or you can't be on the
sidewalk or on a bus drinking.
Well, in other places you can, right?
You can just have a beer on the subway.
So it's a little bit different
policies on alcohol control.
What do you guys think about it?
Do you think it's correct?
Or do you think maybe it's
a little bit too exaggerated?
Come to our website, EnglishPod.
com and tell us about it.
All right, we'll see you guys
there and until next time.
Thanks for downloading and goodbye.